Dahlia Bock

dlbock@gmail.com | +1.718.640.0083 | dlbock.github.io

SUMMARY

I am a seasoned polyglot backend engineer with experience in full-stack and mobile development. I value team collaboration over individuality. I value maintainable, tested, well-documented, and working code over just any kind of code. I'm good at picking up new languages and tools, mastering whatever is needed to get the job done effectively.

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, 2006

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Instana, Austin, TX (01/2019 - Present)

Instana is a fully automated APM solution designed for microservice and cloud-native applications. My team is responsible for Infrastructure and Kubernetes monitoring. This includes, but is not limited to, managing the part of the data processing pipeline that extracts raw data to build a dynamic graph of how entities relate to each other, build & maintain the Kubernetes dashboards on the Instana UI and the Kubernetes sensor, ensure the distribution & installation of the Instana Agent on various Kubernetes platforms & cloud marketplaces.

Technologies: Java, Kafka, Cassandra, Helm

Senior Software Engineer, Billing Management & Provisioning BigCommerce, Austin, TX (10/2017 - 12/2018)

The BMP (Billing Management & Provisioning) team was responsible for the system(s) that processes merchant subscription payments, provisions and manages merchant accounts and all the reporting required. As with maintaining systems that have been around for a while, my responsibilities included monitoring and improving the performance of BMP services while introducing support for new features like VAT and tax jurisdictions. Other responsibilities included mentoring junior teammates.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Scala

Senior Software Engineer, Digital Distribution NBC Universal, New York, NY (01/2017 - 09/2017)

My team and I managed the Android apps for NBCU's TV Everywhere brands (e.g. USA, Syfy, Bravo, Oxygen, E!). These apps were initially built by an external agency but were brought inhouse. Our team introduced automated tests and automated deployments to HockeyApp and onwards to the app stores to streamline feature deployments and bug fixes.

Technologies: Android with Java & Kotlin

Senior Software Engineer, Payments & Subscriptions SoundCloud, New York, NY (09/2014 - 12/2016)

The Payments & Subscriptions team was responsible for the services that perform payments, the services that are the source of record for subscriptions and the services that perform the reconciliation needed for financial reporting. We managed multiple services written in Ruby, Clojure and Scala.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Clojure, Scala, MySQL, RabbitMQ

Senior Engineer

Intent Media, New York, NY (07/2013 - 07/2014)

I was part of the team that managed the tools that orchestrate the deployment of multiple components. We were also responsible for building and maintaining the scripts that facilitate the automated provisioning of new environments. As we were a very small team, we were working towards giving the developers the tools they need to be able to build, deploy and manage their own applications.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails

Senior Consultant

ThoughtWorks (08/2006 - 06/2013)

As ThoughtWorks is a software consulting company, I was privileged to work on many projects spanning multiple business domains and across multiple technology stacks including, but not limited to, web development, Android development, pure backend applications and desktop applications.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Groovy & Grails, Struts, Spring, JSPs, Android development, Java, C# .Net